Yuriy Dybskiy

Vancouver, BC yuriy@dybskiy.com 650.434.2004

Summary

Experienced front-end engineering consultant, passionate about pragmatic, beautiful and efficient solutions to interesting problems, known for being a proactive problem-solver, successful entrepreneur and <u>tech speaker</u>.

Core Technical Skills

HTML5/CSS3 semantic code, JavaScript, Sass, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Git, MongoDB, php, MySQL Improving in: AngularJS, Chrome Dev Tools, Meteor, Tall Data

Professional Experience

PlayHaven (Vancouver, Portland)

Oct. 2012 - Mar. 2013

Front-end Engineer

- Developed a prototype of the new dashboard using AngularJS and Ember.
- Worked on adding features and fixing bugs in the existing Publisher dashboard.

Unbounce (Vancouver)

Feb. 2012 – Aug. 2012

Front-end Engineer

- Developing new app UI and new features using HTML5, Sass, JavaScript and Ruby on Rails.
- Improved app load speed and performance optimizations.

Fabric Engine (Toronto, Montreal)

Aug. 2011 - Dec. 2011

Front-end Engineer

- Improved usability of Fabric development tools as part of open-source project.
- Created jQuery UI theme for the demos and custom designed Bullet Playground demo.

E-Code Studio Inc. (Toronto)

Feb. 2009 – Aug. 2011

Web Development Consultant

Front-end development for startups and web design agencies in Canada, US and UK.

- Attachments.me coded new app designs into HTML5/CSS3 and implemented in RoR.
- <u>Kik.com</u> developed mobile page for "Apps that use Kik" with strong focus on load time optimizations, reducing download size from 100kb+ to 13kb and http requests from 15 to 5.
- Managed a remote development team of five developers, completed 200+ projects for agencies.

Markup4U.com (Ukraine)

Sep. 2007 – Mar. 2009

Project Manager and Co-founder

Co-founded a design-to-XHTML conversion service company which was later acquired.

Education

B.Sc. Mathematics, Kharkiv National University (Ukraine)

2003 - 2007

Hackathons

- My hack <u>Nikon vs. Canon</u> won the Facebook World Hack Vancouver 2012 in "best use of 500px API" category. Source code on <u>GitHub</u>. First commercial application of Meteor.js (Sep. 2012).
- My project <u>photoQuest.me</u> received \$1000 cash prize from Kik and \$5000 in consulting services from Playground at Pixel Hack Day hackathon organized by <u>500px.com</u> (Nov. 2011).